If ever there were a devilish act
committed in this world,
this incident would
definitely have to be it.
The devil, huh?
We State Alchemists are human weapons in the service of the military.
Whenever something comes up,
we are called upon,
and if ordered to,
we must dirty our own hands.
From the point of doing this
or that with other people's lives,
there's not a huge difference between the position we're in and the actions that Tucker took.
That is the reasoning of an adult.
But those children are still so...
Brother...
Brother, the Lt. Colonel...
It's a wasted effort.
It is not possible to reconstruct
a living creature once its life has been lost.
Not for any alchemist.
Who is it going to please to bring an abortive Chimera back to life?
There will be even greater suffering and anguish than this
waiting for you further down the road you have chosen.
As such, you must keep moving forward,
even if you have to force yourselves to accept this.
Accept this, you say?!
There is some purpose you're trying to accomplish, right?
Do you have time
to just stand still?
For crying out loud,
I won't even be able to get in
a good bath with my daughter.
Here?
Yes, sir.
From here on, this is a job for
the Investigations Department.
Stand aside.
This is something awful.
Is this the work of that serial killer?
That guy specializes in young ladies, right?
What's more, this one
hasn't been carved up.
It's almost as if...
they were blown up from the inside or something, from the look of it.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
That's a pretty serious look on your face.
For some reason, it feels like I'm at my wit's end.
And here I thought I was through wavering all over the place.
So then,
what are these orders?
This.
Sort out the materials here and organize them,
and make yourself completely familiar with the results of Tucker's research.
Are you telling me to
take over Tucker's research?
He went about it the wrong way,
but there were portions of Tucker's research that have merit for the military.
Then you can let Tucker
take care of it, can't you?
He's...
dead.
Apparently, his guilt was obvious,
so at the discretion of the higher-ups, he was executed.
You mean this was covered up!
How could they?!
Pledge your loyalty to the military.
That's the main principle
governing State Alchemists.
Say, it looks like Tucker-san was also doing research on the Philosopher's Stone.
Oh? That's nice.
How long are you going to sulk like this, Brother?
The Philosopher's Stone is the ultimate secret to us alchemists, you know.
It increases your faculty without bound
and makes transmutation
beyond principles possible.
In other words, the things that
we weren't able to do could be—
That thing is just a legend!
It's a fairy tale!
But if Tucker-san, a State Alchemist, was doing research on it, then...
Who gives a damn
about his research?!
Al, have you forgotten about Nina?!
I cannot permit it.
Why not?
That serial killer might've done Nina in like that, right?
I'll help out in finding him!
And the work you were ordered to do?
What about analyzing Tucker's research?
I don't want to.
I'll investigate on my own, then.
Okay. In that case,
leave that here.
I intended to.
Brother!
Just a minute!
You're not the only one
who's upset over not being able to do anything for Nina, Brother!
We're alchemists, right?
Catching criminals isn't
something that we can do.
We do research so that if another girl like Nina
ever comes along who we can save...
You...
You... You're the guy from the library.
If you were able to come
and go at the first branch,
does that mean you're
a State Alchemist?
At the time, yeah.
But not anymore.
Is that so?
You're better off.
You're better off, that is...
assuming you don't want to be destroyed by this arm.
Ed and Al sure will be surprised!
They'd never expect me, Winry-chan,
to come all this way and congratulate them!
All righty!
Excuse me, Lt. Hawkeye?
That's all right.
But then, I don't know much about the Philosopher's Stone, either.
At least, I've never heard of it actually existing.
I thought it was just a legend.
I see...
However, I think you'd be better off
not paying any interest in such a thing.
It's said that bad things happen to anyone that gets close to the Philosopher's Stone.
Oh, you're interested in the
Philosopher's Stone, are you?
Who is this?
Th-This gentleman is...
You want to obtain the
Philosopher's Stone, do you?
Yes...
For what reason?
For human—
I mean, I want to recover
something that my brother has lost.
Oh? You must think highly of your brother, huh?
I don't know any particulars myself,
but there are a lot of people who
believe in the Philosopher's Stone.
What's more, once in a while,
I hear stories about alchemists
who have succeeded in creating a Philosopher's Stone.
Such rumors naturally have a way of gathering around the military.
There should be a number of records about it
in the first branch of the Central Library.
Really?
But then, only State Alchemists are allowed to make use of it.
So, a State Alchemist could verify
whether the rumors are true or not.
Führer, why would you listen in
on something like that?
It's good for the youth
to pursue their dreams.
Don't you think so, Lieutenant?
Sure...
See, I'm right!
You think
she's cute too, don't you?
Y-Yeah, I guess...
What do you think?
You think she takes after me?
What can I say? Everyone says so!
Don't bother me, Pops!
There's no need for that kind of talk.
Not when I've been showing you the classified analysis of the serial killer.
You owe me two. One for the train, and one for your wife's delivery.
Oh, yeah?
Well, in any case, we're at a standstill.
The crimes happen within the city, but there are no witnesses.
The bodies are outright sliced up,
but nobody believes that he could do it all in such a short time.
Could he have killed them
and then brought the bodies around?
How much time has passed from the time of death?
Not even the investigators
are clear on that very often.
But between the military and police,
we've opened up and checked the trunk of every car...
coming into the city.
There must be some sort of blind spot.
A car that can hide the bodies,
or something...
Or maybe it's the work of an alchemist...
Alchemists are not murderers!
Uh, are you Edward Elric-san?
Yes.
There's a visitor to see you at the Headquarters reception desk.
A visitor?
Howdy!
Thanks, as usual!
It's all right.
They held the state
certification exams again, right?
Y-Yeah.
Oh, did you hear?
This time, there was a twelve-year-old who passed the test.
I hear he just does this with his hands,
and just like that, he can transmute.
Really?
There, the blond one.
And he's just a child, too.
Oh, come to think of it,
watch out for that one guy.
They say he only
cuts up the pretty ones.
Oh my, are you worried about me?
Sure.
I sure hope they catch him soon.
You bet.
So, about these incidents...
Have you heard anything else?
How long is Ed going to
keep me waiting?
That's a refrigeration unit!
Central sure does have
the latest cars.
How nice!
I sure would like to dismantle it!
I'm afraid having it dismantled would put me out.
I'm sorry!
Is this your truck?
That's right.
This is my
food shop's delivery truck.
Is something the matter?
If you'd like, would you
care to look inside?
Huh? I can?!
Thanks so much!
Huh?
I told her to wait right here.
That's strange...
Elric-san?
Is this...
Winry?
Huh?
Was there a car stopped here?
Yeah, there are always
refrigerated trucks stopping here,
whose dealers serve
the military's cafeteria.
Refrigerated truck?
Something that could hide a body?
It couldn't be...
Elric-san?!
Hey, are you all right?!
Were you kidnapped as well?
Over there, there's someone else.
There is?
Okay, let's take them and get out of here, quick!
I'll be here with you,
so don't worry—
Good morning, junior.
Why, you!
I heard that you can transmute
without using transmutation circles,
so just to be safe...
Let me introduce myself.
I'm the shop's owner, Barry.
A man?
As a reward for making it this far,
let me show you something you'll like.
Winry!
I'm about to craftily dissect this little girl.
Be sure to watch closely, now,
Mr. State Alchemist.
Stop!
Why are you doing this?!
Why?
Well now, because I enjoy it, I suppose.
The first person I killed was my wife.
We were having some
petty argument, you see.
Then, without meaning to, I killed her.
But then, she cut up so neatly, you know?
After that, I started wanting to
cut people up even more neatly.
I wanted everyone to see.
How can one person kill another for something like that?!
Oh, but they can!
Given just the slightest opportunity, a person can kill another.
Stay back!
If they go off to war, it's even easier for one person to kill another.
Why do you suppose that is?
I-I don't know.
It's because people
want to kill each other.
On the battlefield, I saw
a State Alchemist just like you
kill other people with ease.
Splat! Just like that.
No...
No!
Why, you!
What?
Dammit!
Don't!
It'll take more than that to kill me.
They're in here!
Don't move!
Al...
Brother...
Does that hurt?
I thought I was going to get killed.
I really thought that I might die...
I was terrified...
Terribly scared...
Thanks to Hughes-san realizing
that trucks from this same food shop had passed inspections many times,
we somehow managed to get there in time.
Afterward, the case of
Barry the Chopper became famous,
and it would be spoken of as Brother's first distinguished achievement.
Brother...
The Philosopher's Stone
might really exist.
But in order to search for it, you have to be certified as a State Alchemist.
Since I don't have a body,
I can't really feel the terror you felt,
thinking you were going to be killed, Brother.
I'm sure it must've been lonely...
and painful...
Sure, I want my old body back...
to be human again.
Once we find the
Philosopher's Stone,
even if it means having to go against the flow of the rest of the world,
as though nothing will ever come of it...
Having nearly been killed, I realized something...
All I could do was scream.
My mind just went completely blank.
I couldn't even bring myself to think there would be anyone to save me.
For all that we're able to do,
we'll have our hands full just trying to get our own bodies back.
To that end,
whether it means being a dog of the military, or cursed as the devil, I don't care...
But then,
we really aren't devils, much less gods.
We're only human!
Tiny, insignificant humans,
who couldn't even save Nina...
A condition, you say?
I will obey my duties to the military.
As such, I would like to be told all information there is about the Philosopher's Stone.
When I have no other duties, permit me to search for the Philosopher's Stone.
Are you sure you want it to get out that you committed the sin of human transmutation?
Your brother will be
brought into the laboratory
as an extraordinary
example of transmutation.
At least, that's the way I could
pressure you to make sure you stay in line.
Okay, very well.
But you will report to me everything you find out about the Philosopher's Stone.
You have been given
a title from the Führer.
It's quite an ironic title, though.
"We give the name 'Fullmetal' to thee,
Edward Elric, in the name of Führer King Bradley."
Fullmetal?
State Alchemists are given a silver watch,
as well as a second name.
The second name that you will bear is "Fullmetal."
The Fullmetal Alchemist.
I like it. It has an oppressive feel to it.
Sure, I'll take on that name!
To celebrate, you're going to treat me
to all kinds of delicious things!
You've got it backwards, don't you?
I fixed your arm, didn't I?
Brother, I heard that the serial killer
didn't have anything to do with Nina.
No, he seems to have an alibi for that night.
Then, I wonder who it was that wiped out Nina like that...
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 9: "The Dog of the Military's
Silver Watch"
I knew what it would mean to become a State Alchemist
from the very beginning,
Al...